Hi, in this lesson you will learn how to use the common feature for online
completions in Google Antigravity. This feature lets you write or edit code
right inside your data using natural language making quick changes
fast and simple. So let me explain first what is a common.
Common is a feature that brings AI assistance directly into your code editor.
So you will see this pop up with the input where you can type some text.
Instead of switching to the normal chart window in a sidebar you can ask for
code changes right where you could store this. You can just click common plus
i or control plus i if you're using the windows.
So, sync of it is having a conversational with the AI without leaving your
current line of code. You can type what you want and play an
English and antigravity generates or modify the code for your instantly.
So, you can use it in a few ways. You can generate new code, you can edit
existing code. For example, for generate new code you can just
type a cursor in an empty place. Let me close it
and instructions. I need to make my window bigger.
Like a place make a cursor between the methods and click common i.
Yep. And when I need create code I can just activate it
and then type what I want to create in natural language.
For example, we'd like to create a function to get day
at function to get day to get day to day day.
You see it's thinking. It analyzes your request. It looks at surrounding code
for the context and it generates the code right at your cursor position.
And you see it's generated get date.
I am sure it's today day but
Okay. Let's see get the months. You don't talk about time.
Get date. Get the date of the month. You don't talk about time.
Okay. It should be it should by default. I suppose gets today.
Yep. I want to verify it but if you work in a visit you can of course verify
and you can then click accept or reject. Yeah.
Or you can ask a follow-up question right here.
Yeah. I will accept it. Okay. The next option is if you'd like to edit
existing code. Yeah. It also works great for
modified codes that already exist. You can just select the block of
code you want to change. So let's think what we'd like to change.
Oh, let's open the helper. Yeah.
Get month's name.
Okay. Yep. We selected it and then we can click common
eye or control eye if you use in Windows.
Yep. So now we need to ask what specific modification
a bit like. Yeah. For example, these play months in
long or mud like January, April,
real, etc. Don't then we can click submit.
So it will understand what we selected and make the targeted changes
based on your instruction. This gives you focus on one task without
scrolling through the chart, not waiting too much.
Yeah. And you see, it uses the long or mud. We can click accept
changes. Yeah.
Oh, for also fauceting changes, you can use some shortcuts. You can
click common plus enter or control plus enter. Yeah.
Okay. There is also one nice place where you can work with common
features. It's your terminal. I'll expand my terminal right here.
Yeah. And for example, you can just not work with the code
editor. You can also use integrated terminal.
It can help when you need some CLI commands, but you don't
remember the exact syntax. Yeah. You can just open terminal
and ask some questions. For example,
Oh, how so I will also click, uh, click common plus I,
how many files I have in this project.
So yeah, it's just meet the command already type here. Yeah.
How we can check it and I just click common plus enter to accept. Yeah.
And it reduces me to. Yeah. For example, I can ask another question, uh,
what is the size of our first file?
And it will write me exact command how I can check it.
Okay, let's wait a bit.
Yeah, you see the command. If you'd like to reject it, you can click
common plus backspace, yet to reject, but I will click accept to run it.
Uh, okay, the command doesn't work. Yeah, but
you can ask AI to, uh, if it doesn't work, you can ask, yeah, again,
saying that doesn't work. Yeah. For example, you can select the existing code.
Yeah. Like this and click common eye. Uh, let's check if it will work.
Yeah. This command doesn't work.
Okay, so just it's in you command, which is a bit different.
Let's also accept it. Yeah. Now we see the size that it's for kilobytes.
Okay, it works. Uh, I hope this was useful for you.
And now you know how to use command for inline completions,
not only in your code editor, but also in integrated terminal.
Yeah, you can generate new code, edit existing code,
or it can help you with some terminal commands.
Uh, so see you in the next lesson.